A Guide to the Scott and Richards Mercantile Firm Papers
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Scott and Richards Mercantile Firm Papers 1779(1815-1819), 1843, 1879, 1880. 1918
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
5541
This collection consists of ca. 500 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The collection was a gift to the Library from Mr. Edward E. Hartwell of Orange, Virginia, on March 14, 1984, and bears no restrictions.
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of the papers of Scott and Richards, a Fredericksburg, Virginia firm. Included are letters, receipts, checks, accounts, shipping notices, and other papers from the firm's business activities. Most of the letters are addressed either to the firm itself or to John Scott and George B. Richards as individuals. Noted correspondents include G.B. Benson, Catlett Conway, Edwin Conway, Francis Conway, Henry Fields, Henry Fitzhugh, George Pannill, D.W. Pitts, Stanton Slaughter, Baldwin Taliferro, Louis Taliferro, Richard Wanton, and others in Fredericksburg, Orange County, and elsewhere.
Other material in the collection includes letters pertaining to Robert Hayes, Benjamin Day, L.W. Berry, an unsigned poem, a 1918 poster urging support for the ratification of the National Prohibition Amendment, and other miscellaneous papers.
Contents List
- Letter - Crombie and Greenwood to Robert Hayes 1779 Jul 3
- Letter - Mrs. Russell to Col. Jameson and Benjamin Day 1787 Nov 13
- Letter - M. Livingston to Robert Hayes 1792 Jun 1
- Account - Byrd Chamberlayne w/the Estate of Robert Hayes 1792-1793
- Memorandum to various accounts 1795 Jun
- Letter - John Wilson to Mr. Lyon 1796 Feb 28
- Memoranda to various accounts 1796
- Letter - names obliterated 1800 Nov 24
- Receipt from G. Smith to Benjamin Day 1802 Jul 31
- Letter - Edwin Conway to George B. Richards 1809 Mar 1
- Order from Yeoman Smith to Scott and Richards 1815 Nov 11
- Letter - D.W. Pitts to George Richards 1815 Dec 4
- Letter - Stanton Slaughter to Scott and Richards 1815 Dec 15
- Miscellaneous accounts, receipts, and orders ca. 1815 - ca. 1820
- Orders from Law[rence] Taliaferro to Scott and Richards 1816 Aug 20, Dec 12
- Letter - S. Spotswood to George B. Richards [1817]
- Accounts and Orders for 1817 1817-1819
- Miscellaneous accounts, receipts, letters and orders 1818 Jan - Oct
- Miscellaneous accounts, receipts, letters and orders 1818 Nov - Dec
- Protest for non-payment of debt to Mssrs. Page and Triplett by Scott and Richards 1818 Apr 10, Sep 12, 14
- Letter - Robert S. Kipkey to Scott and Richards 1818 Sep 14
- Letter - Charles Taylor to Scott and Richards 1818 Sep 27
- Letter to Scott and Richards 1818 Oct 15
- Letter Catlett Conway to George B. Richards 1818 Oct 20
- Letter - Edwin Conway to George B. Richards 1818 Oct 25
- Letter - Baldwin Taliaferro to Scott and Richards 1818 Oct 27
- Letter - Francis Conway to George B. Richards 1818 Oct 30
- Letter - George Pannill to Scott and Richards 1818 Nov 4
- Letter - Charles Taylor to Scott and Richards 1818 Nov 18
- Letter - Henry Fitzhugh to Scott and Richards 1818 Nov 20
- Letter - D.W. Pitts to George B. Richards 1818 Nov 24
- Letter - Baldwin Taliaferro to Scott and Richards 1818 Dec 4
- Letter - Charles Taylor to Scott and Richards 1818 Dec 5
- Letter - Henry Fields to Scott and Richards 1818 Dec 15
- Letter - Charles Taylor to Scott and Richards 1818 Dec 17
- Notice of shipment to Scott and Richards from Wm. Burgess 1818 Dec 18
- Letter - Baldwin Taliaferro to Scott and Richards 1818 Dec 19
- Letter - Baldwin Taliaferro to Scott and Richards 1819 Jan 22
- Miscellaneous accounts, receipts, letters and orders 1819 Jan - Feb
- Miscellaneous accounts, receipts, letters and orders 1819 Mar - Apr, Dec
- Letter - D. Taliaferro to George B. Richards 1819 Mar 17
- Letter - Louis Taliaferro to Scott and Richards 1819 Mar 25
- Letter - Charles Taylor to Scott and Richards 1819 Mar 30
- Letter - Catlett Conway to GBR 1819 Mar 31
- Letter - Catlett Conway to GBR 1819 Apr 5
- Letter - Stanton Slaughter to Scott and Richards 1819 Apr 16
- Letter - Edwin Conway to GBR 1819 Dec 18
- Notice of shipment of merchandise 1819
- Letter - Cohen's Lottery and Exchange Office to H. Richards 1821 Mar 31
- Letter - G.B. Benson to John Scott 1822
- Letter - Callett Conway to GBR 1828 Oct 7
- Order from W.F. Gray 1828 Nov
- Review of Market and Prices Current (Boston Courier) 1833 Oct 21
- Letter - Richard Wanton to John Scott and Son 1834 Jun 3
- Letter - P.P. Cox to L.W. Berry 1843 Apr 27
- Accounts and price lists 1879
- Telegram - B. Graves to G. Echancellor 1879 Dec
- Market conditions for week ending Oct 21, 1980 1880
- Prohibition Poster 1918
- Unsigned poem n.d.